In this video, I'd like
在这次的课程中（字幕整理：中国海洋大学，黄海广，haiguang2000@qq.com）
to start adapting support vector
我将对支持向量机算法做一些改变
machines in order to develop complex nonlinear classifiers.
以构造复杂的非线性分类器
The main technique for doing that is something called kernels.
我们用"Kernels(核函数)"来达到此目的
Let's see what this kernels are and how to use them.
我们来看看核函数是什么 以及如何使用
If you have a training set that
如果
looks like this, and you
你有一个像这样的训练集
want to find a
然后你希望拟合一个
nonlinear decision boundary to distinguish
非线性的判别边界
the positive and negative examples, maybe
来区别正负实例
a decision boundary that looks like that.
可能是这样的一个判别边界
One way to do so is
一种办法
to come up with a set
是构造
of complex polynomial features, right? So, set of
多项式特征变量 是吧
features that looks like this,
也就是像这样的特征变量集合
so that you end up
这样
with a hypothesis X that
你就能得到一个假设X
predicts 1 if you know
如果θ0加上θ1*X1
that theta 0 and plus theta 1 X1
加上其他的多项式特征变量
plus dot dot dot all those polynomial features is
之和大于0
greater than 0, and
那么就预测为1
predict 0, otherwise.
反之 则预测为0
And another way
这种方法
of writing this, to introduce
的另一种写法
a level of new notation that
这里介绍一个新的概念
I'll use later, is that
之后将会用到
we can think of a hypothesis
我们可以把假设函数
as computing a decision boundary
看成是用这个
using this. So, theta
来计算判别边界 那么
0 plus theta 1 f1 plus
θ0+θ1*f1+
theta 2, f2 plus theta
θ2*f2+θ3*f3
3, f3 plus and so on.
加上其他项
Where I'm going to
在这里
use this new denotation
我将用这几个新的符号
f1, f2, f3 and so
f1 f2 f3等等
on to denote these new sort of features
来表示一系列我将要计算的
that I'm computing, so f1 is
新的特征变量
just X1, f2 is equal
因此 f1就等于X1
to X2, f3 is
f2就等于X2
equal to this one
f3等于这个
here. So, X1X2. So,
X1X2
f4 is equal to
f4等于X1的平方
X1 squared where f5 is
f5等于X2的平方
to be x2 squared and so
等等
on and we seen previously that
我们之前看到
coming up with these high
通过加入这些
order polynomials is one
高阶项
way to come up with lots more features,
我们可以得到更多特征变量
the question is, is
问题是
there a different choice of
能不能选择别的特征变量
features or is there better sort of features than this high order
或者有没有比这些高阶项更好的特征变量
polynomials because you know
因为
it's not clear that this high
我们并不知道
order polynomial is what we want,
这些高阶项是不是我们真正需要的
and what we talked about
我们之前谈到
computer vision talk about when
计算机视觉的时候
the input is an image with lots of pixels.
提到过这时的输入是一个有很多像素的图像
We also saw how using high order polynomials
我们看到如果用高阶项作为特征变量
becomes very computationally
运算量将是非常大的
expensive because there are
因为
a lot of these higher order polynomial terms.
有太多的高阶项需要被计算
So, is there a different or
因此 我们是否有不同的选择
a better choice of the features
或者是更好的选择来构造特征变量
that we can use to plug
以用来
into this sort of
嵌入到
hypothesis form.
假设函数中
So, here is one idea for how to
事实上 这里有一个可以构造
define new features f1, f2, f3.
新特征f1 f2 f3的想法
On this line I am
在这一行中
going to define only three new
我只定义三个
features, but for real problems
特征变量 但是对于实际问题而言
we can get to define a much larger number.
我们可以定义非常多的特征变量
But here's what I'm going to do
但是在这里
in this phase
对于这里的
of features X1, X2, and
特征X1 X2
I'm going to leave X0
我不打算
out of this, the
把X0放在这里
interceptor X0, but
截距X0
in this phase X1 X2, I'm going to just,
但是这里的X1 X2
you know, manually pick a few points, and then
我打算手动选取一些点
call these points l1, we
然后将这些点定义为l1
are going to pick
再选一个
a different point, let's call
不同的点
that l2 and let's pick
把它定为l2
the third one and call
再选第三个点
this one l3, and for
定为l3
now let's just say that I'm
现在 假设我打算
going to choose these three points manually.
只手动选取三个点
I'm going to call these three points line ups, so line up one, two, three.
将这三个点作为标记，标记1，标记2，标记3
What I'm going to do is
我将要做的是
define my new features as follows, given
这样定义新的特征变量
an example X, let me
给出一个实例X
define my first feature f1
将第一个特征变量f1
to be some
定义为
measure of the similarity between
一种相似度的度量
my training example X and
度量实例X与
my first landmark and
第一个标记的相似度
this specific formula that I'm
我将要用来度量相似度的
going to use to measure similarity is
这个公式
going to be this is E to
是这样的 对括号的内容取exp
the minus the length of
负号 X-l1的长度
X minus l1, squared, divided
平方
by two sigma squared.
除以2倍的σ平方
So, depending on whether or not
取决于你之前是否看了
you watched the previous optional video,
上一个可选视频
this notation, you know, this is
这个记号表示
the length of the vector
向量W的长度
W. And so, this thing
因此
here, this X
这里的
minus l1, this is
X-l1
actually just the euclidean distance
就是欧式距离取平方
squared, is the euclidean
是点x与l1之间的
distance between the point x and the landmark l1.
欧式距离
We will see more about this later.
我们之后会更多地谈到这个
But that's my first feature, and
这是我的第一个特征向量
my second feature f2 is
然后是f2
going to be, you know,
它等于
similarity function that measures
对x和l2使用相似度函数
how similar X is to l2 and the game is going to be defined as
度量x与l2的相似度
the following function.
这个相似度函数同上
This is E to the minus of the square of the euclidean distance
对如下值取exp
between X and the second
X到第二个标记之间的欧式距离
landmark, that is what the enumerator is and
这是分子
then divided by 2 sigma squared
再除以2倍的σ平方
and similarly f3 is, you know,
类似的 f3
similarity between X
等于X与l3之间的
and l3, which is
相似度
equal to, again, similar formula.
公式同上
And what this similarity
这个相似度函数是
function is, the mathematical term
用数学术语来说
for this, is that this is
它就是
going to be a kernel function.
核函数
And the specific kernel I'm using
这里我所说的核函数
here, this is actually called a Gaussian kernel.
实际上是高斯核函数
And so this formula, this particular
因此这个公式
choice of similarity function is called a Gaussian kernel.
我们选择的这个相似度公式是高斯核函数
But the way the terminology goes is that, you know, in
但是这个术语
the abstract these different
其实概括了
similarity functions are called kernels and
许多不同的相似度函数
we can have different similarity functions
它们都称作核函数
and the specific example I'm giving here is called the Gaussian kernel.
而我用的这个特定例子是高斯核函数
We'll see other examples of other kernels.
之后我们会见到别的核函数
But for now just think of these as similarity functions.
但是现在就把这个当做相似度函数
And so, instead of writing similarity between
我们通常不需要写
X and l, sometimes we
X和L的相似度
also write this a kernel denoted
有时我们就直接这样写
you know, lower case k between x and one of my landmarks all right.
小写的k 括号里是x和标记l
So let's see what a
现在
criminals actually do and
我们来看看核函数到底可以做什么
why these sorts of similarity
为什么这些相似度函数
functions, why these expressions might make sense.
这些表达式是正确的
So let's take my first landmark. My
先来看看我们的第一个标记
landmark l1, which is
标记l1
one of those points I chose on my figure just now.
l1是我之前在图中选取的几个点中的其中一个
So the similarity of the kernel between x and l1 is given by this expression.
因此x和l1之间的核函数相似度是这样表达的
Just to make sure, you know, we
为了保证
are on the same page about what
你知道
the numerator term is, the
这个分子项是什么
numerator can also be
这个分子也可以
written as a sum from
写为
J equals 1 through N on sort of the distance.
对这个距离求和 j从1到n
So this is the component wise distance
这是向量X和l
between the vector X and
各分量之间的距离
the vector l. And again
再次地
for the purpose of these
在这几张幻灯片中
slides I'm ignoring X0.
我忽略了X0
So just ignoring the intercept
因此我们暂时先不管截距项X0
term X0, which is always equal to 1.
X0总是等于1
So, you know, this is
那么 你现在明白
how you compute the kernel with similarity between X and a landmark.
这就是你通过计算X和标记之间的相似度得到的核函数
So let's see what this function does.
让我们来看看这个函数计算的是什么
Suppose X is close to one of the landmarks.
假设X与其中一个标记点非常接近
Then this euclidean distance
那么这个欧式距离
formula and the numerator will
以及这个分子
be close to 0, right.
就会接近于0 对吧
So, that is this term
这是因为
here, the distance was great,
这里的这个项 是距离的平方
the distance using X and 0
X到l的距离
will be close to zero, and so
接近于0
f1, this is a simple
因此f1
feature, will be approximately E
这个特征变量约等于
to the minus 0 and
对-0取exp
then the numerator squared over 2 is equal to squared
然后除以2倍的σ平方
so that E to the
因此对0取exp
0, E to minus 0,
对-0取exp
E to 0 is going to be close to one.
约等于1
And I'll put the approximation symbol here
我把约等号放在这里
because the distance may
是因为这个距离
not be exactly 0, but
不是严格地等于0
if X is closer to landmark
但是X越接近于L
this term will be close
那么这个项就会越接近于0
to 0 and so f1 would be close 1.
因此f1越接近于1
Conversely, if X is
相反地
far from 01 then this
如果X离L1越远
first feature f1 will
那么f1
be E to the minus
就等于对一个非常大的数字
of some large number squared,
的平方除以2倍σ平方
divided divided by two sigma
再取exp
squared and E to
然后
the minus of a large number
对一个负的大数字取exp
is going to be close to 0.
接近于0
So what these
因此
features do is they measure how
这些特征变量的作用是度量
similar X is from one
X到标记L的相似度
of your landmarks and the feature
并且
f is going to be close
如果X离L非常相近
to one when X is
那么特征变量f
close to your landmark and is
就接近于1
going to be 0 or close
如果X
to zero when X is
离标记L非常远
far from your landmark.
那么f会约等于0
Each of these landmarks.
之前我所画的
On the previous line, I drew
那几个标记点
three landmarks, l1, l2,l3.
l1 l2 l3
Each of these landmarks, defines a new feature
每一个标记点会定义一个新的特征变量
f1, f2 and f3.
f1 f2 f3
That is, given the the
也就是说
training example X, we can
给出一个训练实例X
now compute three new
我们就能计算三个新的特征变量
features: f1, f2, and
f1 f2和f3
f3, given, you know, the three
基于我之前给的
landmarks that I wrote just now.
三个标记点
But first, let's look
但是首先
at this exponentiation function, let's look
我们来看看这个指数函数
at this similarity function and plot
我们来看看这个相似度函数
in some figures and just, you know, understand
我们画一些图
better what this really looks like.
来更好地理解这些函数是什么样的
For this example, let's say I have two features X1 and X2.
比如 假设我们有两个特征变量X1和X2
And let's say my first
假设我们的第一个标记点
landmark, l1 is at
l1
a location, 3 5. So
位于(3,5)
and let's say I set sigma squared equals one for now.
假设σ的平方等于1
If I plot what this feature
如果我画出图
looks like, what I get is this figure.
就是这样的
So the vertical axis, the height
这个纵轴
of the surface is the value
这个曲面的高度是
of f1 and down here
f1的值
on the horizontal axis are, if
再看看水平的坐标
I have some training example, and there
如果我把训练实例画在这里
is x1 and there is x2.
这是X1 这是X2
Given a certain training example, the
给出一个特定的训练实例
training example here which shows
选这里的一个实例
the value of x1 and x2
可以看到X1和X2的值
at a height above the surface,
这个高度
shows the corresponding value of
可以看到这个f1相应的值
f1 and down below this is
下面的这个图
the same figure I had showed,
内容是一样的
using a quantifiable plot, with
但我用的是一个等值线图
x1 on horizontal
x1为水平轴
axis, x2 on horizontal
x2为竖直轴
axis and so, this
那么
figure on the bottom is just
底下的这个图
a contour plot of the 3D surface.
就是这个3D曲面的等值线图
You notice that when
你会发现
X is equal to
当X等于（3，5）的时候
3 5 exactly, then we
这个时候
the f1 takes on the
f1就等于1
value 1, because that's at
因为
the maximum and X
它在最大值上
moves away as X goes
所以如果X往旁边移动
further away then this
离这个点越远
feature takes on values
那么从图中可以看到
that are close to 0.
f1的值就越接近0
And so, this is really a feature,
这就是特征变量f1
f1 measures, you know, how
计算的内容
close X is to the first
也就是X与第一个标记点
landmark and if
的远近程度
varies between 0 and one
这个值在0到1之间
depending on how close X
具体取决于X
is to the first landmark l1.
距离标记点l1到底有多近
Now the other was due on
我在这张幻灯片上要讲的另一项内容是
this slide is show the effects
我们可以看到改变σ平方的值
of varying this parameter sigma squared.
能产生多大影响
So, sigma squared is the parameter of the
σ平方是高斯核函数的参数
Gaussian kernel and as you vary it, you get slightly different effects.
当你改变它的值的时 你会得到略微不同的结果
Let's set sigma squared to be
假设我们让σ平方
equal to 0.5 and see
等于0.5
what we get. We set sigma square to 0.5,
看看我们能得到什么 将σ平方设为0.5
what you find is that the
你会发现
kernel looks similar, except for the
核函数看起来还是相似的
width of the bump becomes narrower.
只是这个突起的宽度变窄了
The contours shrink a bit too.
等值线图也收缩了一些
So if sigma squared equals to 0.5
所以如果我们将σ平方设为0.5
then as you start
我们从X=(3 5)
from X equals 3
开始
5 and as you move away,
往旁边移动
then the feature f1
那么特征变量f1
falls to zero much more
降到0的速度
rapidly and conversely,
会变得很快 与此相反地
if you has increase since
如果你增大了σ平方的值
where three in that
我们假设σ平方等于3
case and as I
在这个例子中
move away from, you know l. So
如果我从点L往旁边移动
this point here is really
这里的这个点
l, right, that's l1 is at
就是L
location 3 5, right. So it's shown up here.
l1所在的坐标为(3,5) 从这里可以看到
And if sigma squared is
如果σ平方很大
large, then as you move
那么
away from l1, the
当你从点l1移走的时候
value of the feature falls
特征变量的值减小的速度
away much more slowly.
会变得比较慢
So, given this definition of
因此 讲完了特征变量的定义
the features, let's see what
我们来看看
source of hypothesis we can learn.
我们能得到什么样的预测函数
Given the training example X, we
给定一个训练实例X
are going to compute these features
我们准备计算出三个特征变量
f1, f2, f3 and a
f1 f2 f3
hypothesis is going to
预测函数的预测值
predict one when theta 0
会等于1 如果θ0加上
plus theta 1 f1 plus theta 2 f2,
θ1*f1 加上 θ2*f2
and so on is greater than or equal to 0.
等等的结果是大于或者等于0的
For this particular example, let's say
对于这个特定的例子而言
that I've already found a learning
假设我们已经找到了一个学习算法
algorithm and let's say that, you know,
并且假设
somehow I ended up with
我已经得到了
these values of the parameter.
这些参数的值
So if theta 0 equals
因此如果θ0等于-0.5
minus 0.5, theta 1 equals
θ1等于1
1, theta 2 equals
θ2等于1
1, and theta 3
θ3等于0
equals 0 And what
我想要做的是
I want to do is consider what
我想要知道会发生什么
happens if we have a
如果
training example that takes
我们有一个训练实例
has location at this
它的坐标在这里
magenta dot, right where I just drew this dot over here.
这个红点 我画的这个点
So let's say I have a training
假设我们有一个训练实例X
example X, what would my hypothesis predict?
我想知道我的预测函数会给出怎样的预测结果
Well, If I look at this formula.
看看这个公式
Because my training example X
因为我的训练实例X
is close to l1, we have
接近于L1
that f1 is going
那么f1
to be close to 1 the because
就接近于1
my training example X is
又因为训练实例X
far from l2 and l3 I
离L2 L3都很远
have that, you know, f2 would be close to
所以 f2就接近于0
0 and f3 will be close to 0.
f3也接近于0
So, if I look at
所以
that formula, I have theta
如果我们看看这个公式
0 plus theta 1
θ0加上θ1
times 1 plus theta 2 times some value.
乘以1加上θ2乘以某个值
Not exactly 0, but let's say close to 0.
不是严格意义上等于0 但是接近于0
Then plus theta 3 times something close to 0.
接着加上θ3乘以一个接近于0的值
And this is going to be equal to plugging in these values now.
这个等于... 再把这些值代入进去
So, that gives minus 0.5
这个是-0.5
plus 1 times 1 which is 1, and so on.
加上1乘以1等于1  等等
Which is equal to 0.5 which is greater than or equal to 0.
最后等于0.5 这个值大于等于0
So, at this point,
因此 这个点
we're going to predict Y equals
我们预测出的Y值是1
1, because that's greater than or equal to zero.
因为大于等于0
Now let's take a different point.
现在我们选择另一个不同的点
Now lets' say I take a
假设
a point out there, if that
这个点
were my training example X, then
如果它是训练实例X
if you make a similar computation,
如果你进行和之前相同的计算
you find that f1, f2,
你发现f1 f2
Ff3 are all going to be close to 0.
f3都接近于0
And so, we have theta
因此 我们得到
0 plus theta 1, f1,
θ0加上θ1*f1
plus so on and this
加上其他项
will be about equal to
最后的结果
minus 0.5, because theta
会等于-0.5
0 is minus 0.5 and
因为θ0等于-0.5
f1, f2, f3 are all zero.
并且f1 f2 f3都为0
So this will be minus 0.5, this is less than zero.
因此最后结果是-0.5 小于0
And so, at this
因此
point out there, we're going to
这个点
predict Y equals zero.
我们预测的Y值是0
And if you do
如果
this yourself for a range
你自己来对大量的点
of different points, be sure to
进行这样相应的处理
convince yourself that if you
你应该可以确定
have a training example that's
如果你有一个训练实例
close to L2, say,
它非常接近于L2
then at this point we'll also predict Y equals one.
那么通过这个点预测的Y值就是1
And in fact, what you end
实际上
up doing is, you know,
你最后得到的结果是
if you look around this boundary, this
如果你看看这个边界线
space, what we'll find is that
这个区域 我们会发现
for points near l1
对于接近L1和L2的点
and l2 we end up predicting positive.
我们的预测值是1
And for points far away from
对于远离
l1 and l2, that's for
L1和L2的店
points far away from these two
对于离这两个标记点非常远的点
landmarks, we end up predicting
我们最后预测的结果
that the class is equal to 0.
是等于0的
As so, what we end up doing,is
我们最后会得到
that the decision boundary of
这个预测函数的
this hypothesis would end
判别边界
up looking something like this where
会像这样
inside this red decision boundary
在这个红色的判别边界里面
would predict Y equals
预测的Y值等于1
1 and outside we predict
在这外面预测的Y值
Y equals 0.
等于0
And so this is
这就是
how with this definition
我们如何通过标记点
of the landmarks and of the kernel function.
以及核函数
We can learn pretty complex non-linear
来训练出非常复杂的非线性
decision boundary, like what I
判别边界的方法
just drew where we predict
就像我刚才画的那个判别边界
positive when we're close to either one of the two landmarks.
当我们接近两个标记点中任意一个时 预测值就会等于1
And we predict negative when we're
否则预测值等于0
very far away from any
如果这些点离标记点
of the landmarks.
非常远
And so this is part of
这就是核函数这部分
the idea of kernels of and
的概念
how we use them with the
以及我们如何
support vector machine, which is that
在支持向量机中使用它们
we define these extra features using
我们通过标记点和相似性函数
landmarks and similarity functions
来定义新的特征变量
to learn more complex nonlinear classifiers.
从而训练复杂的非线性边界
So hopefully that gives you
我希望刚才讲的内容能够
a sense of the idea of
帮助你更好的理解核函数的概念
kernels and how we could
以及我们如何使用它
use it to define new features for the Support Vector Machine.
在支持向量机中定义新的特征变量
But there are a couple of questions that we haven't answered yet.
但是还有一些问题我们并没有做出回答
One is, how do we get these landmarks?
其中一个是 我们如何得到这些标记点
How do we choose these landmarks?
我们怎么来选择这些标记点
And another is, what
另一个是
other similarity functions, if any,
其他的相似度方程是什么样的 如果有其他的话
can we use other than the
我们能够用其他的相似度方程
one we talked about, which is called the Gaussian kernel.
来代替我们所讲的这个高斯核函数吗
In the next video we give
在下一个视频中
answers to these questions and put
我们会回答这些问题
everything together to show how
然后把所有东西都整合到一起
support vector machines with kernels
来看看支持向量机如何通过核函数的定义
can be a powerful way
有效的学习
to learn complex nonlinear functions.
复杂非线性函数